Word2Vec is perhaps one of the most popular examples of word embeddings used in practice.
Word2Vec 可能是词嵌入在实践中运用最广泛的例子
As the name Word2Vec indicates,
顾名思义 Word2Vec
it transforms words to vectors.
是将词转换成向量
But what the name doesn't give away is how that transformation is performed.
但是这个名字并没有体现出如何进行转换
The core idea behind Word2Vec is this,
Word2Vec 的核心概念是
a model that is able to predict a given word,
一个模型能根据相邻词
given neighboring words, or vice versa,
预测特定词 反之亦然
predict neighboring words for a given word is
预测特定词的相邻词
likely to capture the contextual meanings of words very well.
从而能捕捉词的上下文意义
And these are, in fact,
实际上 这是
two flavors of Word2Vec models,
Word2Vec 模型的两种功能
one where you are given neighboring words called continuous bag of words,
一种是给出相邻词 称为连续词袋
and the other where you are given the middle word called Skip-gram.
另一种是给出中间词 称为 Skip-gram
In the Skip-gram model,
在 Skip-gram 模型中
you pick any word from a sentence,
可以从句子中挑选任何词
convert it into a one-hot encoded vector and feed it into a neural network or
将其转换成独热编码向量 将其输入神经网络或其他概率模型
some other probabilistic model that is designed to
这个模型用于预测周围词 也就是上下文
Using a suitable loss function,
使用适当的损失函数
optimize the weights or parameters of the model and repeat this
优化模型的权重或参数并重复
till it learns to predict context words as best as it can.
直到模型学会了尽可能地预测语境词
Now, take an intermediate representation like a hidden layer in a neural network.
现在将中间表示法作为神经网络中的隐藏层
The outputs of that layer for a given word become the corresponding word vector.
这一层特定词的输出变成对应的词向量
The Continuous Bag of Words variation also uses a similar strategy.
连续词袋模型采用的策略相似
This yields a very robust representation of words
由于每个词的意义分布在向量中
because the meaning of each word is distributed throughout the vector.
这种词表示法非常稳健
The size of the word vector is up to you,
词向量的大小由你决定
how you want to tune performance versus complexity.
取决于你想如何平衡性能和复杂度
It remains constant no matter how many words you train on,
无论训练时使用多少词 向量的大小都保持不变
unlike Bag of Words, for instance,
而词袋不同
where the size grows with the number of unique words.
其大小会随着唯一词数量的增加而增加
And once you pre-train a large set of word vectors,
一旦预训练了一大组词向量
you can use them efficiently without having to transform again and again,
就可以有效率地使用这些词向量 无需多次转换
just store them in a lookup table.
只需将其存储在查找表中即可
Finally, it is ready to be used in deep learning architectures.
最后便可直接用于深度学习架构
For example, it can be used as the input vector for recurrent neural nets.
例如 可以将其用作循环神经网络的输入向量
It is also possible to use RNNs to learn even better word embeddings.
还可使用循环神经网络训练出更好的词嵌入模型
Some other optimizations are possible that further reduce the model and
还有其它优化方式 可进一步降低模型和
training complexity such as representing the output words using Hierarchical Softmax,
训练复杂度 例如 使用 Hierarchical Softmax 表示输出词
computing loss using Sparse Cross Entropy, et cetera.
使用稀疏交叉熵计算损失等